YUNUSA ABDULWAHAB (ACA)

Address: Block J, Flat 4, Trikania Estate, Nnamdi Azikiwe Express Way, Kaduna. Contact: 08074720555 abdulwahabyunusa4@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A professional accountant with years of progressive experience in audit and accountancy, with great interest in financial technology. As an auditor, I carry out audits, reviews on internal control systems and accountancy services for companies. Having good knowledge on front end development, with practical skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React & Git. Creative, goal driven, able to navigate high-stress situations and achieve set targets under tight schedule.

PERSONAL DATA

First Name: Abdulwahab Surname: Yunusa State of Origin: Edo State

Date of Birth: 20th December 1993.

Nationality: Nigeria

WORK HISTORY

Institution: Musa Bello Learning Centre (ICAN Kaduna Lecture Centre)

Job Title/Location: Lecturer – Kaduna State.

Period: 2021 to Date.

Duties & Responsibilities

• Deliver lectures, seminars, and tutorials.

- Design, prepare and develop courses, modules, and teaching materials.
- Develop and implement new methods of teaching.
- Assess and review student performance.

Work History

- Lectures financial accounting in foundation level.
- Facilitator on Introduction to International Financial Reporting Standard (IFRS) presented at Industrial Training Fund (ITF) Kaduna, May 10th, 2022.
- Facilitator on Internal Audit and Investigation Report, presented at Industrial Training Fund (ITF) Kaduna, May 25th, 2022.

Institution: UF Idiagi & Co (Chartered Accountants)

Job Title/Location: Audit Manager - Kaduna State.

Period: 2018 to Date.

Duties & Responsibilities:

- Developed audit plan based on audit standards and government regulations.
- Performed audits and generate audit reports with recommendations.
- Reviewed and recommend improvements to existing audit procedures.
- Review and assess completion of audits.
- Coordinate with clients about auditing practices.
- Maintain and update financial databases including audit findings.
- Coordinate with the management to take necessary action on audit findings.
- Provided training and mentoring to audit team members.

Work History

- i. Represented the firm as tax consultant to Sunshine Quarry Nigeria Limited on tax fraud investigation with The Economic and Financial Crimes Commission, EFCC. For the period 3rd October 2022 to date.
- ii. Team lead, Tax liability examination at Ashmed Specialist Hospital Aguwa, Kaduna for the period year 2019, 2020, 2021 and 2022. Responsibilities includes:
 - Coordination of team to achieve set goals.
 - Consolidation of team member's work
 - Preparation and presentation of tax report

- iii. Audit Team lead to Hadiraf Cereal and Oil Mill 2022 with the following responsibilities:
 - Assessment of client internal control system
 - Preparation of Audit report
 - Pair review
- iv. Audit team leader to Sindyan Nigeria Limited 2021 with the following responsibilities:
 - Assessment of client internal control system
 - Preparation of Audit report
 - Pair review
- v. Part of audit team on Stamp Duty Audit 2021 in recovery of back years stamp duty in relation to the following agencies:
 - National Office for Technology Acquisition and Promotion (NOTAP).
 - National space Research and Development Agency.
 - National Biotechnology Development Agency.
 - National Board for Technological Incubation.
 - Nigeria Atomic Energy Commission.
- vi. Team lead, inventory and stock count exercise at Sidi and son's supermarket 2021 with the following responsibilities:
 - Coordination of team to achieve set goals.
 - Update of client inventory management system to reflect actual stock level.
 - Preparation of report on inventory and stock count exercise
- vii. Part of audit team to Ashmed Specialist Hospital 2020 with the following responsibilities:
 - Assessment of client's internal control system
 - Extraction of client's Trail balance and
- viii. Part of audit team to Independent National Electoral Commission (INEC) Zamfara, Sokoto and Kebbi State, with the following responsibilities:
 - Vouching of client financial records
 - Extraction of data from client's source document
 - Stock Count
 - ix. Part of audit team to Grand Central Hotel Kano, year 2018 with the following responsibilities:
 - Extraction of data from client's source document
 - Extraction of client's trail balance

EDUCATION

Bachelors in accounting, Federal University Kashere West Africa Examination Council (WACE).	2017 2012
PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION	
Institute of Chartered Accountants of Nigeria (ICAN).	2020
Higher Diploma in Python Programming language	2021

SKILLS

- i. Proficient in Excel, Words and Power point.
- ii. Profound knowledge of audit techniques.
- **iii.** Ability to oversee business, financial, functional and people management activities.
- iv. Python programming Language, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Git.
- **v.** Worked with EPOS (An inventory management system)
- vi. Worked with sage 50 and quick books.

vii. Good communication skills

POSITION HELD

- i. Sport Director, Nigeria Universities Accounting Students Association (NUASA) Federal University Kashere 2016.
- ii. ELCOM Chairman, (NUASA) Federal University kashere 2017.
- iii. Financial Secretary, Stainable Development Goal (SDGs) Group National Youth Service Corps (NYSC) 2018.
- iv. Served as a presiding officer during 2019 national elections.

REFEREE

Available on request.